(music playing)
My name is Linda Sands. I was born in 1967
Along with my twin sister Kathy.
We both have severe disabilities of cerebral palsy.
(music playing)
When our mother became ill,
she had to have surgery and other things take place;
and when she is your main caregiver, and she is down
it kind of put all three of us in a nursing
home.
When you've been independent, and parents raise you
promising you would never be in a nursing home,
and you end up in one, it kind of lowers your
self-esteem somewhat.
You're living under somebody else's
regimen and rules, and how they run things,
and what's available to you and what's not.
Kathy and I just turned forty a week after it happened,
and that was hardly a wonderful way to celebrate your fortieth birthday.
(music playing)
It's our first place in quite a while, and
the roll-in shower gives us a sense
of independence and freedom
and peace of mind knowing that we can function
in this house freely.
Disabled people are just like
anyone else.
We feel. We have the same joys,
same desires, same hopes
and we go through the challenges
of everyday life as well,
along with our disability.
(music playing)
Housing is a basic implement in life.
and if people can't afford it,
they're missing one of their fundamental rights
I believe.
Without those opportunities for everyone,
how can we truly be free?
And let everyone have a chance at happiness
and contentment and a feeling of belonging
in their community.
When the disabled are happy, it can help only
make the rest of us happy.
(music playing)